John J. Herman

546 Morgan Street NE Unit B • Atlanta, Georgia 30308 • (770) 241-6512 • hermanjohn2@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/john-joseph-herman/ • github.com/hermanjohn2 • hermanjohn2.github.io/

SUMMARY

Honest, dependable, hard-working Full Stack Web Developer with 8 years of experience in management, staffing, training, and business development. Received a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Georgia Institute of Technology, where I gained skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, MySQL and MongoDB. Demonstrates strong problem-solving qualities, adaptability, and excellent interpersonal skills. Applied aspects of UX and agile development in a recent project where I worked on a team of two to develop a MERN stack application that helps users build a collaborative music queue.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development-------August 2020 Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Playlistr, Developer, Georgia Institute of Technology ------July 2020 – current

- Design, develop and deploy a collaborative queue building, MERN stack, application that focuses on UX
- Utilize agile development to ensure project is ready for demonstration by deadline

Yogurtland Georgia, *General Manager,* Atlanta, GA-------August 2011 – current

- Manage operations of three store locations within Georgia
- Interview, hire, train, and oversee over 200 employees in total
- Reduce expenses by minimizing waste, setting pay rates, and managing inventory levels
- Process documentation for new hires, including direct deposit information, and tax forms such as I-9s and W-4s
- Write, update, and implement policy to ensure the business meets corporate compliance expectations
- Compile monthly, quarterly and annual reports to track sale trends and implement cost-saving changes

Yogurt After Dark, Event Manager, Atlanta, GA ------January 2016 – November 2018

- Launched a start-up company that implements an innovative frozen drink concept
- Managed events by working directly with caterers to create a memorable experience for all guests